

Camila Waz

UX Design Engineer

Dublin, Ireland

hello@camilawaz.com

LinkedIn Website CodePen GitHub

Skills

Design

Information Architecture Ideation Wireframes Prototyping Interface Design

Coding

HTML CSS JavaScript Angular.js WordPress

Tools

Adobe XD Figma Miro **InVision** Protopie Photoshop InDesign

I aim to work at the intersection between design and front-end development using UX design principles in alignment with HTML, CSS, JavaScript (and libraries) to bring creative and scalable solutions into the world wide web. I'm a NN/g certified UX professional and have also pursued other qualifications focused on User Experience as well as Adobe Creative Suite training.

Work Experience

Net Affinity / UX Design Engineer

Jun 2018 - Present, Dublin - Ireland

Responsible for Prototyping, Design and Front End Development in a fast-paced Agile environment.

- Ideating concepts and creating prototypes for client-facing and admin interfaces of our products using software like Adobe XD, Invision and Protopie
- UI Design Evolving prototypes into high fidelity designs that are passed on to the development team
- Working closely with the development team to assure the best front end practices are being used across our products
- Coding animations, interactions, UI elements and components using web languages (HTML, SCSS/SASS) in an Angular JS application
- Implementing new workflows to work better with CSS, increasing productivity and reuse of code

Net Affinity / UX/UI Web Developer

May 2017 - Jun 2018, Dublin - Ireland

Responsible for creating effective solutions to optimize the development workflow with the team, involving:

- Build and implementation of website templates, landing pages and email marketing
- Overview and Refactoring of the company's internal component library
- Introducing and training the web development team on different technologies (eg Gulp.js) and workflows
- Optimization of existent projects and templates for Google Page Speed
- Maintenance work for existing clients
- Maintenance of the styling (SCSS/CSS) and script (JavaScript/jQuery) structure for internal products (eg Booking Engine)

During this time I also had the opportunity to build websites for some well-known hotels in Ireland and the UK which includes Galgorm Spa & Golf Resorts, Seafield Hotel & SPA and Lake Hotel Killarney.

Pipoca Digital / Front End Developer

Jun 2016 - Jan 2017, Remote - Brazil

For Pipoca Digital I worked as a remote employee coding Photoshop designs into interactive web projects. My key responsibilities were fast development of styles for websites (CSS/SASS) focusing on responsive solutions. At this company, I had the opportunity to contribute to a private repository with components designed to improve existing projects and decrease the development time.

Qualitare / Front End Developer

Sep 2014 - May 2016, Paraíba - Brazil

Coding Photoshop designs into interactive web projects, mostly for landing pages. At this company I had the opportunity to work closely with the design team, giving suggestions in the projects and increasing my skills.

Education, Courses & Workshops

Universidade Federal da Paraíba (UFPB) / Bachelor's Degree 2012 - 2016, Paraíba - Brazil

Field Of Study: Communication in Digital Media

UX Certification / Nielsen Norman Group November 2019, London - England

Courses: Assessing UX Designs Using Proven Principles, Lean UX and Agile, Managing User

Experience Strategy, The One-Person UX Team, UX Deliverables.

Verification - Code: 1032376



Activities & Hobbies

DublinCSS Organiser

Community Meetup about CSS in Dublin. Since June 2019

Conferences

I love to attend conferences and meetups about various subjects that contribute to my professional and personal development.

ColorDrops

Side project exploring design and hand lettering. Instagram: @colordrops_

Public Speaking

Share what I know is a part of my day-to-day, so I'm starting to present talks about Design and Web Development (focusing on CSS).